# **NIRA TAMANG**

+9779863206913 • neera678@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/nira-tamang-063a1a200/ • https://github.com/niratamang70

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced and highly dedicated frontend developer with over 2+ years of experience. I am confident in analyzing clients' requirements and translating them into highly functional web applications while leaving room for creativity and scalability. I excel at working collaboratively within diverse teams and can also thrive as an individual contributor. My communication skills enable me to convey technical and non-technical information with ease effectively.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Kantipur Engineering College, TU

Bachelor in Computer Engineering

Dhapakhel,Lalitpur 2016 - 2021

## **Himalayan International Higher Secondary School**

Higher Secondary Education Board (+2 Science)

Narayantar,Kathmandu 2014 - 2016

## Mahendra Boudha Higher Secondary School

School Leaving Certificate

Boudha,Kathmandu 2014

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Language: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML/CSS, C, C++, Python

Framework: React, Next, Vue, React native

**Developer Tools:** Git,GitLab **API Platform:** Swagger,Postman

Frontend Framework: Bootstrap, Antd, Chakra UI
Testing Framework: Jest, Vitest, React Testing Library

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Mid Frontend Developer**

Oct 2023 - present

Khalti Pvt. Ltd Bakhundole,Lalitpur

- Developed and maintained responsive web applications using React and technologies around the Javascript ecosystem.
- Engaged in sprint planning, daily stand-ups, sprint reviews, and retrospective meetings to ensure that our project deliverables met the client's requirements and aligned with the project specifications.
- · Documented project ideas and workflows while effectively managing change logs.
- Actively involved in the initial project requirement meeting, contributing insights and gathering essential information.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including designers, product managers, and other developers, to understand project requirements and deliver high-quality solutions.
- Participated in architecture design discussions and stack decision meetings, where the technological framework and infrastructure were determined.

## **Frontend Developer**

Dec 2021 - Oct 2023

E.K Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Kupondole, Lalitpur

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams at E.K Solutions Pvt. Ltd to develop and implement responsive and user-friendly web applications.
- Utilized modern frontend frameworks, such as React.js, to build dynamic and interactive interfaces.
- Optimized website performance through code refactoring, and implementation of best practices.
- Integrated third-party APIs and libraries to enhance application functionality and user experience.

- Conducted thorough testing and debugging to ensure high-quality and bug-free code.
- Actively participated in time estimation and sprint planning sessions, leveraging my analytical skills and domain knowledge to contribute valuable insights and suggestions.

#### **Frontend Developer Intern**

Sept 2021 - Dec 2021

E.K Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Kupondole,Lalitpur

- Applied Web Design and Development Principles.
- Actively participated in code reviews and contributed to continuous improvement by providing constructive feedback and suggesting optimizations.
- Demonstrated proficiency in JavaScript by developing a sophisticated blog application.
- · Learned to organize workflow using GitLab.
- Developed proficiency in understanding and working with popular frontend frameworks expanding my knowledge of frontend development.
- Acquired proficiency in code optimization techniques, improving the performance and efficiency of web applications

#### **PROJECTS**

### E5/Events | Khalti

Dec 2023 - Present

- E5 is an event ticket booking system using KPG (Khalti Payment Gateway).
- Segregated events and registration processes for event participation, implementing them as server-side rendered functionalities.
- Implemented Khalti Payment Gateway for payment.
- Improved performance by minimizing re-render in React and optimizing server-side render.

Silkroad | Khalti Oct 2023 - Present

- Silkroad is a payment collection ecosystem for the merchants in Khalti realm. It is a dashboard system for merchants, who would primarily look after the transactions, branches, and field agents
- Evolved in initial project requirement meetings and then involved in architecture design and stack decision meetings where the technological framework and infrastructure best suited were determined.
- Developed the system with a login feature by providing each using specific roles and UI permission.
- Implemented a notification center, integrating alert notifications efficiently.
- · Visually represented the data using a pie, doughnut, and bar chart.

#### Base station, CRM | Ekbana

Aug 2021 - Present

- Conducted Research to Meet Assigned Task Requirements and Analyzed and interpreted project requirements and specifications,
- Collaborated closely with project managers for time estimation of the project.

#### Testmink | Ekbana

June 2021 - Aug 2021

- Utilized React.js and RTK Query as the frontend framework to develop interactive and dynamic user interfaces for efficient and intuitive user experiences.
- Implemented state management and data fetching using RTK Query, a powerful data fetching and caching library, to streamline API interactions and optimize frontend performance.
- Actively participated in requirement analysis and clarification sessions with QA to clarify user stories and ensure
  accurate implementation of frontend features.

#### Himalaya General Insurance, E2E | Ekbana

Mar 2021- June 2021

- Implemented best practices for frontend development, including code modularity, scalability, and performance optimization, resulting in efficient and maintainable codebases.
- Implemented dynamic form fields and conditional logic to adapt the form based on specific insurance policies and claim types, improving the overall user experience and simplifying the claims submission process.

# Meyco Order Portal | Ekbana

Jan 2021 - Feb 2021

· Worked on password reset feature.

 Translated design into well-structured and reusable React components, following best practices for modularity and maintainability.

## **Travel Recommendation (Course Project)**

2019 - 2020

- Developed a web application to recommend places with information. It shows places popular using K-nearest neighbor algorithms.
- Used Python as backend language with Django framework and HTML/CSS, Javascript as frontend language.
- Implemented Incremental model to develop the application as the application has complex features that need to be designed, developed, and tested incrementally until the product is finished.

## Theft Reporting System (Course Project)

2018 - 2019

- Theft Reporting System is an Android application to report thefts online. It is a platform for making theft report management easy and more reliable for the public.
- Developed with XML as frontend and Firebase server and Java as backend language with an android studio as IDE.A prototyping methodology is used for the development which allows rapid development and testing ideas.
- Acquired knowledge of mobile application development with more skills in object-oriented language.

# **Supermarket Management System (Course Project)**

2016

- It is developed using C++ programming and It allows users to add products to the system and manage purchase-related activities.
- Gained experience with object-oriented language and functionalities.

#### **OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Tutor** Apr 2021 – Mar 2022

 Provided in-person tuition to grade six students during the pandemic to support their learning needs as they faced challenges with online classes.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Nepali: Native Speaker

English: Fluent Hindi: Fluent